<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>United States Department of Agriculture (USDA)</origin>
        <origin>National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS)</origin>
        <pubdate>20210201</pubdate>
        <title>Cropland Data Layer, New York, 2020</title>
        <edition>2020 Edition</edition>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>USDA-NASS Cropland Data Layer</sername>
          <issue>New York 2010</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>USDA, NASS Marketing and Information Services Office, Washington,
            D.C.</pubplace>
          <publish>USDA, NASS</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <othercit>NASS maintains a Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ's) section on the CDL website at
          &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/SARS1a.php&gt;. The data is
          available free for download through CropScape at
          &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt;. The data is also available free for
          download through the Geospatial Data Gateway at
          &lt;https://datagateway.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt;.</othercit>
        <onlink>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/catalog/cugir-009110</onlink>
        <onlink>&lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt;</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The USDA, NASS Cropland Data Layer (CDL) is a raster, geo-referenced, crop-specific
        land cover data layer. The 2020 CDL has a ground resolution of 30 meters. The CDL is
        produced using satellite imagery from the Landsat 8 OLI/TIRS sensor, the Disaster Monitoring
        Constellation (DMC) DEIMOS-1, the ISRO ResourceSat-2 LISS-3, and the ESA SENTINEL-2 sensors
        collected during the current growing season. Some CDL states used additional satellite
        imagery and ancillary inputs to supplement and improve the classification. These additional
        sources can include the United States Geological Survey (USGS) National Elevation Dataset
        (NED) and the imperviousness and canopy data layers from the USGS National Land Cover
        Database 2016 (NLCD 2016). Agricultural training and validation data are derived from the
        Farm Service Agency (FSA) Common Land Unit (CLU) Program. The most current version of the
        NLCD is used as non-agricultural training and validation data. Please refer to the
        'Supplemental_Information' Section of this metadata file for a complete list of all imagery,
        ancillary data, and training/validation data used to generate this state's CDL. The strength
        and emphasis of the CDL is agricultural land cover. Please note that no farmer reported data
        are derivable from the Cropland Data Layer.</abstract>
      <purpose>The purpose of the Cropland Data Layer Program is to use satellite imagery to (1)
        provide planted acreage estimates to the Agricultural Statistics Board for the state's major
        commodities and (2) produce digital, crop-specific, categorized geo-referenced output
        products.</purpose>
      <supplinf>If the following table does not display properly, then please visit the following
        website to view the original metadata file
        &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/metadata/meta.php&gt;. USDA,
        National Agricultural Statistics Service, 2020 New York Cropland Data Layer CLASSIFICATION
        INPUTS: DEIMOS-1 DATE 20200420 SCENE IDENTIFIER 701 DEIMOS-1 DATE 20200507 SCENE IDENTIFIER
        7B1 DEIMOS-1 DATE 20200521 SCENE IDENTIFIER 83A DEIMOS-1 DATE 20200620 SCENE IDENTIFIER 87E
        DEIMOS-1 DATE 20200621 SCENE IDENTIFIER 882 RESOURCESAT-2 LISS-3 DATE 20191011 PATH 289
        RESOURCESAT-2 LISS-3 DATE 20200715 PATH 287 RESOURCESAT-2 LISS-3 DATE 20200822 PATH 285
        RESOURCESAT-2 LISS-3 DATE 20200915 PATH 285 RESOURCESAT-2 LISS-3 DATE 20200916 PATH 290
        LANDSAT 8 OLI/TIRS REAL-TIME DATE 20200503 PATH 014 LANDSAT 8 OLI/TIRS REAL-TIME DATE
        20200609 PATH 017 LANDSAT 8 OLI/TIRS REAL-TIME DATE 20200706 PATH 014 LANDSAT 8 OLI/TIRS
        REAL-TIME DATE 20200908 PATH 014 LANDSAT 8 OLI/TIRS REAL-TIME DATE 20200915 PATH 015 USGS,
        NATIONAL ELEVATION DATASET USGS, NATIONAL LAND COVER DATABASE 2016 TREE CANOPY USGS,
        NATIONAL LAND COVER DATABASE 2016 IMPERVIOUSNESS USDA, NASS CROPLAND DATA LAYERS 2014-2019
        SENTINEL-2A DATE 20191009 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 140 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20191013 RELATIVE ORBIT
        NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20191019 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 140 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200503
        RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200513 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2A
        DATE 20200520 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200527 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011
        SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200609 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200615 RELATIVE ORBIT
        NUMBER 140 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200616 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200622
        RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200702 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2A
        DATE 20200706 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200709 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054
        SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200719 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200726 RELATIVE ORBIT
        NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200811 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200814
        RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 140 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200821 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2A
        DATE 20200904 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2A DATE 20200920 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097
        SENTINEL-2A DATE 20201010 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20191001 RELATIVE ORBIT
        NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20191005 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20191008
        RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20191011 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2B
        DATE 20191015 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20191021 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097
        SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200425 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200502 RELATIVE ORBIT
        NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200505 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200512
        RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200521 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 140 SENTINEL-2B
        DATE 20200604 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200617 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097
        SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200621 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200704 RELATIVE ORBIT
        NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200707 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200710
        RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 140 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200823 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B
        DATE 20200912 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200915 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097
        SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200919 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200922 RELATIVE ORBIT
        NUMBER 054 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20200925 RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 097 SENTINEL-2B DATE 20201009
        RELATIVE ORBIT NUMBER 011 TRAINING AND VALIDATION: USDA, FARM SERVICE AGENCY 2020 COMMON
        LAND UNIT DATA USGS, NATIONAL LAND COVER DATABASE 2016 NOTE: The final extent of the CDL is
        clipped to the state boundary even though the raw input data may encompass a larger
        area.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20191001</begdate>
          <enddate>20201231</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>2020 growing season</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>None planned</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
          <bounding>
            <westbc>-79.974336</westbc>
            <eastbc>-70.596893</eastbc>
            <northbc>45.838882</northbc>
            <southbc>40.116635</southbc>
          </bounding>
        </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>farming</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>Global Change Master Directory (GCMD) Science Keywords</themekt>
        <themekey>Earth Science &gt; Biosphere &gt; Terrestrial Ecosystems &gt; Agricultural
          Lands</themekey>
        <themekey>Earth Science &gt; Land Surface &gt; Land Use/Land Cover &gt; Land
          Cover</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>crop cover</themekey>
        <themekey>cropland</themekey>
        <themekey>agriculture</themekey>
        <themekey>land cover</themekey>
        <themekey>crop estimates</themekey>
        <themekey>DEIMOS-1</themekey>
        <themekey>ISRO ResourceSat-2 LISS-3</themekey>
        <themekey>ESA SENTINEL-2</themekey>
        <themekey>Landsat</themekey>
        <themekey>CropScape</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
              <themekt>CUGIR Category</themekt>
              <themekey>agriculture</themekey>
<themekey>environment</themekey>
<themekey>landcover</themekey>
            </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>New York</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2020</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The USDA, NASS Cropland Data Layer is provided to the public as is and is considered
      public domain and free to redistribute. The USDA, NASS does not warrant any conclusions drawn
      from these data. If the user does not have software capable of viewing GEOTIF (.tif) or ERDAS
      Imagine (.img) file formats then we suggest using the CropScape website
      &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt;.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA, NASS, Spatial Analysis Research Section</cntorg>
          <cntper>USDA, NASS, Spatial Analysis Research Section staff</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>1400 Independence Avenue, SW, Room 5029 South Building</address>
          <city>Washington</city>
          <state>District of Columbia</state>
          <postal>20250-2001</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-727-9540</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>855-493-0447</cntfax>
        <cntemail>SM.NASS.RDD.GIB@usda.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <browse>
              <browsen>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/91/10/preview.png</browsen>
              <browsed>preview of the dataset</browsed>
              <browset>PNG</browset>
            </browse>
    <datacred>USDA, National Agricultural Statistics Service</datacred>
    <secinfo>
      <secsys>None</secsys>
      <secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
      <sechandl>None</sechandl>
    </secinfo>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Enterprise; ERDAS Imagine Version 2018
      &lt;https://www.hexagongeospatial.com/&gt;; ESRI ArcGIS Version 10.7
      &lt;https://www.esri.com/&gt;; Rulequest See5.0 Release 2.11a
      &lt;http://www.rulequest.com/&gt;; NLCD Mapping Tool version
      'NLCD_for_IMAGINE_ver_16_0_0_build_199_2018-09-12' &lt;https://www.mrlc.gov/&gt;. ERDAS
      Imagine is used in the pre- and post- processing of all raster-based data. ESRI ArcGIS is used
      to prepare the vector-based Farm Service Agency (FSA) Common Land Unit (CLU) training and
      validation data. Rulequest See5.0 is used to create a decision-tree based classifier. The NLCD
      Mapping Tool is used to apply the See5.0 decision-tree via ERDAS Imagine. This is a departure
      from older versions of the CDL that were created using in-house software (Peditor) based upon
      a maximum likelihood classifier approach. Check this section and the 'Process Description'
      section of the specific state and year metadata file to verify what methodology was
      used.</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>If the following table does not display properly, then please visit this internet
        site &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/metadata/meta.php&gt; to
        view the original metadata file. USDA, National Agricultural Statistics Service, 2020 New
        York Cropland Data Layer STATEWIDE AGRICULTURAL ACCURACY REPORT Crop-specific covers only
        *Correct Accuracy Error Kappa ------------------------- ------- -------- ------ -----
        OVERALL ACCURACY** 340,658 73.0% 27.0% 0.659 Cover Attribute *Correct Producer's Omission
        User's Commission Cond'l Type Code Pixels Accuracy Error Kappa Accuracy Error Kappa ----
        ---- ------ -------- ----- ----- -------- ----- ----- Corn 1 147492 87.8% 12.2% 0.850 87.5%
        12.5% 0.846 Sorghum 4 368 30.7% 69.3% 0.307 69.2% 30.8% 0.691 Soybeans 5 40581 76.9% 23.1%
        0.756 84.7% 15.3% 0.838 Sunflower 6 2 3.9% 96.1% 0.039 50.0% 50.0% 0.500 Sweet Corn 12 911
        45.2% 54.8% 0.451 77.5% 22.5% 0.774 Barley 21 235 33.9% 66.1% 0.338 65.1% 34.9% 0.651 Durum
        Wheat 22 0 n/a n/a n/a 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 Spring Wheat 23 35 21.7% 78.3% 0.217 55.6% 44.4%
        0.555 Winter Wheat 24 15034 83.1% 16.9% 0.828 84.6% 15.4% 0.843 Dbl Crop WinWht/Soybeans 26
        0 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 n/a n/a n/a Rye 27 301 18.3% 81.7% 0.183 57.6% 42.4% 0.575 Oats 28 2145
        46.3% 53.7% 0.461 70.2% 29.8% 0.701 Millet 29 1 1.8% 98.2% 0.018 50.0% 50.0% 0.500 Speltz 30
        38 25.3% 74.7% 0.253 65.5% 34.5% 0.655 Alfalfa 36 60803 74.2% 25.8% 0.717 76.5% 23.5% 0.742
        Other Hay/Non Alfalfa 37 57240 65.7% 34.3% 0.623 69.9% 30.1% 0.668 Buckwheat 39 126 39.3%
        60.7% 0.392 78.3% 21.7% 0.783 Sugarbeets 41 182 39.8% 60.2% 0.398 61.7% 38.3% 0.617 Dry
        Beans 42 3318 56.8% 43.2% 0.566 75.3% 24.7% 0.752 Potatoes 43 1053 60.3% 39.7% 0.602 87.5%
        12.5% 0.874 Other Crops 44 5 3.1% 96.9% 0.031 41.7% 58.3% 0.417 Misc Vegs &amp; Fruits 47 0
        0.0% 100.0% 0.000 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 Onions 49 747 78.4% 21.6% 0.784 79.2% 20.8% 0.792
        Cucumbers 50 122 55.5% 44.5% 0.554 78.7% 21.3% 0.787 Peas 53 712 56.9% 43.1% 0.569 74.9%
        25.1% 0.749 Tomatoes 54 0 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 Herbs 57 0 0.0% 100.0% 0.000
        n/a n/a n/a Clover/Wildflowers 58 796 30.6% 69.4% 0.305 58.6% 41.4% 0.585 Sod/Grass Seed 59
        414 74.9% 25.1% 0.749 80.4% 19.6% 0.804 Fallow/Idle Cropland 61 2306 33.5% 66.5% 0.332 52.8%
        47.2% 0.525 Cherries 66 16 25.4% 74.6% 0.254 69.6% 30.4% 0.696 Peaches 67 13 18.6% 81.4%
        0.186 36.1% 63.9% 0.361 Apples 68 2174 71.2% 28.8% 0.711 77.7% 22.3% 0.776 Grapes 69 1745
        79.1% 20.9% 0.790 88.6% 11.4% 0.886 Christmas Trees 70 58 30.5% 69.5% 0.305 57.4% 42.6%
        0.574 Other Tree Crops 71 0 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 n/a n/a n/a Pears 77 12 14.1% 85.9% 0.141
        60.0% 40.0% 0.600 Triticale 205 377 25.4% 74.6% 0.253 73.1% 26.9% 0.730 Carrots 206 89 69.5%
        30.5% 0.695 76.7% 23.3% 0.767 Broccoli 214 16 30.2% 69.8% 0.302 88.9% 11.1% 0.889 Peppers
        216 0 n/a n/a n/a 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 Greens 219 1 1.8% 98.2% 0.018 16.7% 83.3% 0.167 Plums
        220 0 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 Strawberries 221 0 0.0% 100.0% 0.000 0.0% 100.0%
        0.000 Squash 222 208 39.9% 60.1% 0.399 84.9% 15.1% 0.849 Dbl Crop WinWht/Corn 225 0 0.0%
        100.0% 0.000 n/a n/a n/a Dbl Crop Triticale/Corn 228 159 33.7% 66.3% 0.337 85.9% 14.1% 0.859
        Pumpkins 229 33 20.1% 79.9% 0.201 40.2% 59.8% 0.402 Dbl Crop Barley/Corn 237 0 n/a n/a n/a
        0.0% 100.0% 0.000 Blueberries 242 1 2.4% 97.6% 0.024 12.5% 87.5% 0.125 Cabbage 243 789 65.3%
        34.7% 0.652 87.5% 12.5% 0.875 *Correct Pixels represents the total number of independent
        validation pixels correctly identified in the error matrix. **The Overall Accuracy
        represents only the FSA row crops and annual fruit and vegetables (codes 1-61, 66-80, 92 and
        200-255). FSA-sampled grass and pasture. Non-agricultural and NLCD-sampled categories (codes
        62-65, 81-91 and 93-199) are not included in the Overall Accuracy. The accuracy of the
        non-agricultural land cover classes within the Cropland Data Layer is entirely dependent
        upon the USGS, National Land Cover Database (NLCD 2016). Thus, the USDA, NASS recommends
        that users consider the NLCD for studies involving non-agricultural land cover. For more
        information on the accuracy of the NLCD please reference
        &lt;https://www.mrlc.gov/&gt;.</attraccr>
      <qattracc>
        <attraccv>Classification accuracy is generally 85% to 95% correct for the major
          crop-specific land cover categories. See the 'Attribute Accuracy Report' section of this
          metadata file for the detailed accuracy report.</attraccv>
        <attracce>The strength and emphasis of the CDL is crop-specific land cover categories. The
          accuracy of the CDL non-agricultural land cover classes is entirely dependent upon the
          USGS, National Land Cover Database (NLCD 2016). Thus, the USDA, NASS recommends that users
          consider the NLCD for studies involving non-agricultural land cover. These definitions of
          accuracy statistics were derived from the following book: Congalton, Russell G. and Kass
          Green. Assessing the Accuracy of Remotely Sensed Data: Principles and Practices. Boca
          Raton, Florida: CRC Press, Inc. 1999. The 'Producer's Accuracy' is calculated for each
          cover type in the ground truth and indicates the probability that a ground truth pixel
          will be correctly mapped (across all cover types) and measures 'errors of omission'. An
          'Omission Error' occurs when a pixel is excluded from the category to which it belongs in
          the validation dataset. The 'User's Accuracy' indicates the probability that a pixel from
          the CDL classification actually matches the ground truth data and measures 'errors of
          commission'. The 'Commission Error' represent when a pixel is included in an incorrect
          category according to the validation data. It is important to take into consideration
          errors of omission and commission. For example, if you classify every pixel in a scene to
          'wheat', then you have 100% Producer's Accuracy for the wheat category and 0% Omission
          Error. However, you would also have a very high error of commission as all other crop
          types would be included in the incorrect category. The 'Kappa' is a measure of agreement
          based on the difference between the actual agreement in the error matrix (i.e., the
          agreement between the remotely sensed classification and the reference data as indicated
          by the major diagonal) and the chance agreement which is indicated by the row and column
          totals. The 'Conditional Kappa Coefficient' is the agreement for an individual category
          within the entire error matrix.</attracce>
      </qattracc>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The Cropland Data Layer (CDL) has been produced using training and independent validation
      data from the Farm Service Agency (FSA) Common Land Unit (CLU) Program (agricultural data) and
      United States Geological Survey (USGS) National Land Cover Database (NLCD). More information
      about the FSA CLU Program can be found at &lt;https://www.fsa.usda.gov/&gt;. More information
      about the NLCD can be found at &lt;https://www.mrlc.gov/&gt;. The CDL encompasses the entire
      state unless noted otherwise in the 'Completeness Report' section of this metadata
      file.</logic>
    <complete>The entire state is covered by the Cropland Data Layer.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The Cropland Data Layer retains the spatial attributes of the input imagery. The
          Landsat 8 OLI/TIRS imagery was obtained via download from the USGS Global Visualization
          Viewer (Glovis) website &lt;https://glovis.usgs.gov/&gt;. Please reference the metadata on
          the Glovis website for each Landsat scene for positional accuracy. The majority of the
          Landsat data is available at Level 1T (precision and terrain corrected). The DEIMOS-1
          imagery used in the production of the Cropland Data Layer is orthorectified to a radial
          root mean square error (RMSE) of approximately 10 meters.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO)</origin>
            <pubdate>2020</pubdate>
            <title>ResourceSat-2 LISS-3</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Indian Space Research Organisation HQ, Department of Space, Government of
                India Antariksh Bhavan, New BEL Road, Bangalore 560 231</pubplace>
              <publish>Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO)</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The ISRO ResourceSat-2 LISS-3 satellite sensor operates in four spectral bands
              at a spatial resolution of 24 meters. Additional information about the data can be
              obtained at &lt;https://www.isro.gov.in/&gt;. Refer to the 'Supplemental Information'
              Section of this metadata file for specific scene date, path, row and quadrants used as
              classification inputs. For the 2020 CDL Program, the imagery was resampled to 30
              meters to match the Landsat spatial resolution. The resample used cubic convolution,
              rigorous transformation.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24 meter</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online download</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20191001</begdate>
              <enddate>20201231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>LISS-3</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>European Space Agency (ESA)</origin>
            <pubdate>2020</pubdate>
            <title>SENTINEL-2</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>European Commission, Brussels (Belgium)</pubplace>
              <publish>Copernicus - European Commission</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The ESA SENTINEL-2 satellite sensor operates in twelve spectral bands at
              spatial resolutions varying from 10 to 60 meters. Additional information about the
              data can be obtained at &lt;http://www.esa.int/&gt;. Refer to the 'Supplemental
              Information' Section of this metadata file for specific scene date, path, row and
              quadrants used as classification inputs. For the 2020 CDL Program, the imagery was
              resampled to 30 meters to match the Landsat spatial resolution. The resample used
              cubic convolution, rigorous transformation.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>10 meter</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online download</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20191001</begdate>
              <enddate>20201231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>SENTINEL-2</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Elecnor Deimos Imaging</origin>
            <pubdate>2020</pubdate>
            <title>DEIMOS-1</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Elecnor Deimos Imaging, Valladolid, Spain</pubplace>
              <publish>Astrium GEO Information Services</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The DEIMOS-1 satellite sensor operates in three spectral bands at a spatial
              resolution of 22 meters. Additional information about DEIMOS-1 data can be obtained at
              &lt;https://www.deimos-imaging.com/&gt;. Refer to the 'Supplemental Information'
              Section of this metadata file for specific scene date, path, row and quadrants used as
              classification inputs. The DEIMOS-1 imagery was resampled to 30 meters to match the
              Landsat spatial resolution. The resample used cubic convolution, rigorous
              transformation.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>22 meter</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online download</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20191001</begdate>
              <enddate>20201231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Deimos-1</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States Geological Survey (USGS), Earth Resources Observation and Science
              (EROS)</origin>
            <pubdate>2020</pubdate>
            <title>Landsat 8 Operational Land Imager and Thermal Infrared Sensor (OLI/TIRS)</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota 57198-001</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS, EROS</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The Landsat 8 OLI/TIRS data are free for download through the following
              website &lt;https://glovis.usgs.gov/&gt;. Additional information about Landsat data
              can be obtained at &lt;https://www.usgs.gov/centers/eros&gt;. Refer to the
              'Supplemental Information' Section of this metadata file for specific scene date, path
              and rows used as classification inputs.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>30 meter</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online download</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
              <begdate>20191001</begdate>
              <enddate>20201231</enddate>
            </rngdates>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Landsat 8</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States Geological Survey (USGS) Earth Resources Observation and Science
              (EROS) Data Center</origin>
            <pubdate>2009</pubdate>
            <title>The National Elevation Dataset (NED)</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota 57198 USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS, EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The USGS NED Digital Elevation Model (DEM) is used as an ancillary data source
              in the production of the Cropland Data Layer. More information on the USGS NED can be
              found at
              &lt;https://www.usgs.gov/core-science-systems/national-geospatial-program/national-map&gt;.
              Refer to the 'Supplemental Information' Section of this metadata file for the complete
              list of ancillary data sources used as classification inputs.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>30 meter</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NED</srccitea>
        <srccontr>spatial and attribute information used in land cover spectral signature
          analysis</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States Geological Survey (USGS) Earth Resources Observation and Science
              (EROS) Data Center</origin>
            <pubdate>2019</pubdate>
            <title>National Land Cover Database 2016 (NLCD 2016)</title>
            <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Sioux Falls, South Dakota 57198 USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USGS, EROS Data Center</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>The NLCD 2016 was used as ground training and validation for non-agricultural
              categories. Additionally, the USGS NLCD 2016 Imperviousness layer was used as
              ancillary data sources in the Cropland Data Layer classification process. The NLCD2016
              Tree Canopy data layer was not published in time for use in CDL production, so the
              NLCD 2011 Tree Canopy data was used. More information on the NLCD 2016 and NLCD 2011
              can be found at &lt;https://www.mrlc.gov/&gt;. Refer to the 'Supplemental Information'
              Section of this metadata file for the complete list of ancillary data sources used as
              classification inputs.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>30 meter</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>unknown</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>NLCD</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Raw data used in land cover spectral signature analysis</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Farm Service Agency
              (FSA)</origin>
            <pubdate>2020</pubdate>
            <title>USDA, FSA Common Land Unit (CLU)</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Salt Lake City, Utah 84119-2020 USA</pubplace>
              <publish>USDA, FSA Aerial Photography Field Office</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Access to the USDA, Farm Service Agency (FSA) Common Land Unit (CLU) digital
              data set is currently limited to FSA and Agency partnerships. During the current
              growing season, producers enrolled in FSA programs report their growing intentions,
              crops and acreage to USDA Field Service Centers. Their field boundaries are digitized
              in a standardized GIS data layer and the associated attribute information is
              maintained in a database known as 578 Administrative Data. This CLU/578 dataset
              provides a comprehensive and robust agricultural training and validation data set for
              the Cropland Data Layer. Additional information about the CLU Program can be found at
              &lt;https://www.fsa.usda.gov/&gt;.</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>4800</srcscale>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>2020</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition, updated annually</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>FSA CLU</srccitea>
        <srccontr>spatial and attribute information used in the spectral signature training and
          validation of agricultural land cover</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>OVERVIEW: The United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), National
          Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) Cropland Data Layer (CDL) Program is a unique
          agricultural-specific land cover geospatial product that is produced annually in
          participating states. The CDL Program builds upon NASS' traditional crop acreage
          estimation program and integrates Farm Service Agency (FSA) grower-reported field data
          with satellite imagery to create an unbiased statistical estimator of crop area at the
          state and county level for internal use. It is important to note that the internal acreage
          estimates, most closely aligned with planted acres, produced using the CDL are not simple
          pixel counting. It is more of an 'Adjusted Census by Satellite.' SOFTWARE: ERDAS Imagine
          is used in the pre- and post- processing of all raster-based data. ESRI ArcGIS is used to
          prepare the vector-based training and validation data. Rulequest See5.0 is used to create
          a decision tree based classifier. The NLCD Mapping Tool is used to apply the See5.0
          decision-tree via ERDAS Imagine. DECISION TREE CLASSIFIER: This Cropland Data Layer used
          the decision tree classifier approach. Using a decision tree classifier is a departure
          from older versions of the CDL which were created using in-house software (Peditor) based
          upon a maximum likelihood classifier approach. Decision trees offer several advantages
          over the more traditional maximum likelihood classification method. The advantages include
          being: 1) non-parametric by nature and thus not reliant on the assumption of the input
          data being normally distributed, 2) efficient to construct and thus capable of handling
          large and complex data sets, 3) able to incorporate missing and non-continuous data, and
          4) able to sort out non-linear relationships. GROUND TRUTH: As with the maximum likelihood
          method, decision tree analysis is a supervised classification technique. Thus, it relies
          on having a sample of known ground truth areas in which to train the classifier. Older
          versions of the CDL (prior to 2006) utilized ground truth data from the annual June
          Agricultural Survey (JAS). Beginning in 2006, the CDL utilizes the very comprehensive
          ground truth data provided from the FSA Common Land Unit (CLU) Program as a replacement
          for the JAS data. The FSA CLU data have the advantage of natively being in a GIS and
          containing magnitudes more of field level information. Disadvantages include that it is
          not truly a probability sample of land cover and has bias toward subsidized program crops.
          Additional information about the FSA data can be found at
          &lt;https://www.fsa.usda.gov/&gt;. The most current version of the NLCD is used as
          non-agricultural training and validation data. INPUTS: The CDL is produced using satellite
          imagery from the Landsat 8 OLI/TIRS sensor, the Disaster Monitoring Constellation (DMC)
          DEIMOS-1, the ISRO ResourceSat-2 LISS-3, and the ESA SENTINEL-2 sensors collected during
          the current growing season. The DEIMOS-1 and UK-DMC 2 imagery was resampled to 30 meters
          using cubic convolution, rigorous transformation to match the traditional Landsat spatial
          resolution. Some CDL states used additional satellite imagery and ancillary inputs to
          supplement and improve the classification. These additional sources can include the United
          States Geological Survey (USGS) National Elevation Dataset (NED) and the imperviousness
          and canopy data layers from the USGS National Land Cover Database 2016 (NLCD 2016). Please
          refer to the 'Supplemental_Information' Section of this metadata file for a complete list
          of all imagery and ancillary data used to generate this state's CDL. ACCURACY: The
          accuracy of the land cover classifications are evaluated using independent validations
          data sets generated from the FSA CLU data (agricultural categories) and the NLCD
          (non-agricultural categories). The Producer's Accuracy is generally 85% to 95% correct for
          the major crop-specific land cover categories. See the 'Attribute Accuracy Report' section
          of this metadata file for the full accuracy report. PUBLIC RELEASE: The USDA, NASS
          Cropland Data Layer is considered public domain and free to redistribute. The official
          website is &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/SARS1a.php&gt;. The
          data is available free for download through CropScape
          &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt; and the Geospatial Data Gateway
          &lt;https://datagateway.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt;. Please note that in no case are farmer
          reported data revealed or derivable from the public use Cropland Data Layer.</procdesc>
        <procdate>2020</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>USDA, NASS, Spatial Analysis Research Section</cntorg>
              <cntper>USDA, NASS, Spatial Analysis Research Section staff</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
              <address>1400 Independence Avenue, SW, Room 5029 South Building</address>
              <city>Washington</city>
              <state>District of Columbia</state>
              <postal>20250-2001</postal>
              <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>800-727-9540</cntvoice>
            <cntfax>855-493-0447</cntfax>
            <cntemail>SM.NASS.RDD.GIB@usda.gov</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
    <cloud>0</cloud>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Raster</direct>
        <rastinfo>
          <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
          <rowcount>16925</rowcount>
          <colcount>22229</colcount>
        </rastinfo>
      </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
          <albers>
            <stdparll>29.500000</stdparll>
            <stdparll>45.500000</stdparll>
            <longcm>-96.000000</longcm>
            <latprjo>23.000000</latprjo>
            <feast>0.000000</feast>
            <fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
          </albers>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>30</absres>
            <ordres>30</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <overview>
      <eaover>The Cropland Data Layer (CDL) is produced using agricultural training data from the
        Farm Service Agency (FSA) Common Land Unit (CLU) Program and non-agricultural training data
        from the most current version of the United States Geological Survey (USGS) National Land
        Cover Database (NLCD). The strength and emphasis of the CDL is crop-specific land cover
        categories. The accuracy of the CDL non-agricultural land cover classes are entirely
        dependent upon the NLCD. Thus, the USDA, NASS recommends that users consider the NLCD for
        studies involving non-agricultural land cover.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>If the following table does not display properly, then please visit the following
        website to view the original metadata file
        &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/metadata/meta.php&gt;. Data
        Dictionary: USDA, National Agricultural Statistics Service, 2020 Cropland Data Layer Source:
        USDA, National Agricultural Statistics Service The following is a cross reference list of
        the categorization codes and land covers. Note that not all land cover categories listed
        below will appear in an individual state. Raster Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: NO
        DATA, BACKGROUND 0 Categorization Code Land Cover "0" Background Raster Attribute Domain
        Values and Definitions: CROPS 1-60 Categorization Code Land Cover "1" Corn "2" Cotton "3"
        Rice "4" Sorghum "5" Soybeans "6" Sunflower "10" Peanuts "11" Tobacco "12" Sweet Corn "13"
        Pop or Orn Corn "14" Mint "21" Barley "22" Durum Wheat "23" Spring Wheat "24" Winter Wheat
        "25" Other Small Grains "26" Dbl Crop WinWht/Soybeans "27" Rye "28" Oats "29" Millet "30"
        Speltz "31" Canola "32" Flaxseed "33" Safflower "34" Rape Seed "35" Mustard "36" Alfalfa
        "37" Other Hay/Non Alfalfa "38" Camelina "39" Buckwheat "41" Sugarbeets "42" Dry Beans "43"
        Potatoes "44" Other Crops "45" Sugarcane "46" Sweet Potatoes "47" Misc Vegs &amp; Fruits
        "48" Watermelons "49" Onions "50" Cucumbers "51" Chick Peas "52" Lentils "53" Peas "54"
        Tomatoes "55" Caneberries "56" Hops "57" Herbs "58" Clover/Wildflowers "59" Sod/Grass Seed
        "60" Switchgrass Raster Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: NON-CROP 61-65
        Categorization Code Land Cover "61" Fallow/Idle Cropland "63" Forest "64" Shrubland "65"
        Barren Raster Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: CROPS 66-80 Categorization Code Land
        Cover "66" Cherries "67" Peaches "68" Apples "69" Grapes "70" Christmas Trees "71" Other
        Tree Crops "72" Citrus "74" Pecans "75" Almonds "76" Walnuts "77" Pears Raster Attribute
        Domain Values and Definitions: OTHER 81-109 Categorization Code Land Cover "81" Clouds/No
        Data "82" Developed "83" Water "87" Wetlands "88" Nonag/Undefined "92" Aquaculture Raster
        Attribute Domain Values and Definitions: NLCD-DERIVED CLASSES 110-195 Categorization Code
        Land Cover "111" Open Water "112" Perennial Ice/Snow "121" Developed/Open Space "122"
        Developed/Low Intensity "123" Developed/Med Intensity "124" Developed/High Intensity "131"
        Barren "141" Deciduous Forest "142" Evergreen Forest "143" Mixed Forest "152" Shrubland
        "176" Grassland/Pasture "190" Woody Wetlands "195" Herbaceous Wetlands Raster Attribute
        Domain Values and Definitions: CROPS 195-255 Categorization Code Land Cover "204" Pistachios
        "205" Triticale "206" Carrots "207" Asparagus "208" Garlic "209" Cantaloupes "210" Prunes
        "211" Olives "212" Oranges "213" Honeydew Melons "214" Broccoli "215" Avocados "216" Peppers
        "217" Pomegranates "218" Nectarines "219" Greens "220" Plums "221" Strawberries "222" Squash
        "223" Apricots "224" Vetch "225" Dbl Crop WinWht/Corn "226" Dbl Crop Oats/Corn "227" Lettuce
        "228" Dbl Crop Triticale/Corn "229" Pumpkins "230" Dbl Crop Lettuce/Durum Wht "231" Dbl Crop
        Lettuce/Cantaloupe "232" Dbl Crop Lettuce/Cotton "233" Dbl Crop Lettuce/Barley "234" Dbl
        Crop Durum Wht/Sorghum "235" Dbl Crop Barley/Sorghum "236" Dbl Crop WinWht/Sorghum "237" Dbl
        Crop Barley/Corn "238" Dbl Crop WinWht/Cotton "239" Dbl Crop Soybeans/Cotton "240" Dbl Crop
        Soybeans/Oats "241" Dbl Crop Corn/Soybeans "242" Blueberries "243" Cabbage "244" Cauliflower
        "245" Celery "246" Radishes "247" Turnips "248" Eggplants "249" Gourds "250" Cranberries
        "254" Dbl Crop Barley/Soybeans</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
        <distrib>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>Cornell University</address>
              <city>Ithaca</city>
              <state>New York</state>
              <postal>14853</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
          </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>Cornell University provides these geographic data "as is". Cornell
          University makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of
          information contained in the geographic data. Cornell University further
          makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of
          the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for
          determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these
          files have been processed successfully on computers at Cornell University,
          no warranty is made by Cornell University regarding the use of these data
          on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply
          any such warranty.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
        <digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>GeoTIFF</formname>
              <formcont>zipped geotiff</formcont>
              <filedec>zip</filedec>
              <transize>39.05</transize>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/91/10/cugir-009110.zip</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC XML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/91/10/fgdc.xml</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>HTML metadata</formname>
              <formcont>FGDC HTML metadata</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir-data.s3.amazonaws.com/00/91/10/fgdc.html</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><digform>
            <digtinfo>
              <formname>OGC:WMS</formname>
              <formcont>WMS, from GeoServer</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
              <onlinopt>
                <computer>
                  <networka>
                    <networkr>https://cugir.library.cornell.edu/geoserver/cugir/wms?version=1.1.0&amp;request=GetMap&amp;layers=cugir009110&amp;bbox=-80.25565929,39.944967590000005,-70.31556970999999,46.010549409999996&amp;width=256&amp;height=156&amp;srs=EPSG:4326&amp;format=image/png</networkr>
                  </networka>
                </computer>
              </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
          </digform><fees>None</fees></stdorder>
      </distinfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>USDA, NASS Customer Service</cntorg>
          <cntper>USDA, NASS Customer Service Staff</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>1400 Independence Avenue, SW, Room 5038-S</address>
          <city>Washington</city>
          <state>District of Columbia</state>
          <postal>20250-9410</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-727-9540</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>855-493-0447</cntfax>
        <cntemail>SM.NASS.RDD.GIB@usda.gov</cntemail>
        <cntinst>Please visit the official website
          &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/SARS1a.php&gt; for
          distribution details. The Cropland Data Layer is available free for download at
          &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt; and
          &lt;https://datagateway.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt;. Distribution issues can also be directed to
          the NASS Customer Service Hotline at 1-800-727-9540.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Cropland Data Layer - New York 2020</resdesc>
    <distliab>Disclaimer: Users of the Cropland Data Layer (CDL) are solely responsible for
      interpretations made from these products. The CDL is provided 'as is' and the USDA, NASS does
      not warrant results you may obtain using the Cropland Data Layer. Contact our staff at
      (SM.NASS.RDD.GIB@usda.gov) if technical questions arise in the use of the CDL. NASS does
      maintain a Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ's) section on the CDL website at
      &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/SARS1a.php&gt;.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>GEOTIFF</formname>
          <formverd>2020</formverd>
          <formcont>GEOTIFF</formcont>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>&lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt;</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
            <accinstr>The CDL is available online and free for download from the CropScape website
              &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt;. It is also available free for download
              from the Geospatial Data Gateway website
              &lt;https://datagateway.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt;.</accinstr>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>Please visit the official website
        &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/SARS1a.php&gt; for distribution
        details. The Cropland Data Layer is available free for download at
        &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt; and
        &lt;https://datagateway.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt;. Distribution issues can also be directed to the
        NASS Customer Service Hotline at 1-800-727-9540.</fees>
      <ordering>The CDL is available online and free for download from the CropScape website
        &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt;. The Cropland Data Layer is also available
        free for download from the NRCS Geospatial Data Gateway at
        &lt;https://datagateway.nrcs.usda.gov/&gt;. If you experience problems downloading all years
        of CDL data through the Geospatial Data Gateway then you can try to use the 'Direct Data
        Download' link in the lower right-hand corner of their webpage.</ordering>
    </stdorder>
    <custom>For a list of other states and years of available CDL data please visit
      &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt; or
      &lt;https://www.nass.usda.gov/Research_and_Science/Cropland/SARS1a.php&gt;. Distribution
      issues can also be directed to the NASS Customer Service Hotline at 1-800-727-9540.</custom>
    <techpreq>If the user does not have software capable of viewing GEOTIF (.tif) or ERDAS Imagine
      (.img) file formats then we suggest using the CropScape website
      &lt;https://nassgeodata.gmu.edu/CropScape/&gt;.</techpreq>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
      <metd>20210720</metd>
      <metc>
        <cntinfo>
          <cntorgp>
            <cntorg>Albert R. Mann Library</cntorg>
          </cntorgp>
          <cntaddr>
            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
            <address>Albert R. Mann Library</address>
            <city>Ithaca</city>
            <state>New York</state>
            <postal>14853</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
          </cntaddr>
          <cntvoice>607-255-5406</cntvoice>
          <cntemail>mann-ref@cornell.edu</cntemail>
        </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
